<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A blog by Wade</title>
    <description>A site to host blog posts and ideas about what I am doing</description>
    <link>http://WadeOler.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://WadeOler.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 07:07:07 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 07:07:07 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>3D Printing with NinjaFlex</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the main reasons I purchased a 3D printer was the availability of exotic filaments like NinjaFlex. What I didnt realize is how much time and effort it would take to get a quality print from some of these filaments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I show my friends and colleges see when I show a 3D print, all they are seeing is just the end result. It doesn’t show how many hours that are spent with failed prints, clogged hot ends, and overall trials and errors it takes to get a single semi-decent print. When 3D printing the first question you have to ask yourself is ‘What material are you going to print with?’. This inherently causes multiple and sometimes all of the above issues. This is because not only the type of filament (ABS, PLA, or TPU) comes into play but the quality of the material can make a HUGE difference and this varies drastically from brand to brand. And most of the time it takes many test prints to get your setting just right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NinjaFlex is unlike any material that I have printed and that led to many jams and failed printes. Hopefully these settings will lower someones trial and error time. So on that note, its time to end my rambling and list my settings!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ninjaflex&quot;&gt;NinjaFlex&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bed
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bare Aluminum heated bed
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Purple Glue Stick for adhesion (no tape)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Temperature
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;40 C&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hotend
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Direct Drive Extruder
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;245 C&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Draw Speed
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;20 mm/s&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Extrusion width
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;.4 mm&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Layer Height
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;.2 mm&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Infill Speed
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;90%&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Infill Density
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;15%&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just my personal setting from guessing and checking, your mileage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 13:38:34 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://WadeOler.com/3D-Printing-with-NinjaFlex.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://WadeOler.com/3D-Printing-with-NinjaFlex.html</guid>
        
        <category>3DPrinting</category>
        
        <category>Printing</category>
        
        <category>CAD</category>
        
        <category>Prusai3</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>3DPrinting</category>
        
        <category>NinjaFlex</category>
        
        <category>HairDrainTrap</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
